（ゼツ）やめろ　なんでこうなんだよ！
Stop! Why would you do this?
うわ～っ！
（サスケ）外で試すか。
Let's test these outside,
shall we?
These eyes…
この眼は　闇がよく見える。
see the darkness
quite well…
（重吾）サスケと香燐は無事だろうか。
I wonder if Sasuke and Karin
are okay?
（水月）そんな
心配するだけ損かもよ。
I wouldn't waste time
thinking about that.
（重吾）なんでだ。
サスケと香燐が生きて→
Why?
Say that Karin and Sasuke
are alive and well…
２人でいるとして
僕たちが２人を見つけて→
And you and I find them.
感動の再会ってなると思う？
Do you really think it'll be
a touching emotional reunion?
いいかい。　香燐は
サスケといちゃつきあいたい。
See… Karin wants to get
hot and heavy with Sasuke.
Which means the two of us
will be in the way.
なら　僕たちは
２人の邪魔者ってこった。
そうか。　ならどうする？
I see… So what'll we do?
刀集めを続けるか？
Keep gathering blades?
もちろん。　２人の邪魔をする。
We'll meddle, of course!
それが　刀集めの次に
僕の楽しみだしね。
That's what I enjoy most,
next to gathering swords.
（重吾）
サスケたちを捜す　で　いいんだな。
So we're going to look
for Sasuke and Karin?
（水月）
まずは　大蛇丸のアジトをまわるか。
First, let's go check out
Orochimaru's hideout!
Four Tails, the King of
Sage Monkeys
（ナルト）来てくれたんだ
カカシ先生　ゲキマユ先生！
You came, Kakashi Sensei!
Bushier Brow Sensei!
（カカシ）第７班の教え子が
頑張り過ぎてんのに→
You know I can't just sit back
and relax
while my student from Team 7
is working hard!
休んでるわけにはいかないでしょ。
Oh! Him! He's got a Sharingan
あ　アイツってば
写輪眼で輪廻眼がつながってて→
and a Rinnegan that are linked,
left eye to right eye…and…!
左目と右目で　えっと
左の胸に杭が刺さってて…。
And there's a rod sticking out of
the left side of the chest…and…!
えっと…。
（ガイ）落ち着け。
Calm down.
You're not making sense.
何言ってるか　わからんぞ。
右目が　写輪眼。　左目が輪廻眼。
The right eye is Sharingan.
The left eye is Rinnegan.
左胸に　ペインと同じ杭か。
なるほどね。
And he has the same rod
Pain had in his left chest.
So I see.
さすがだな　カカシ。　すごい理解力だ。
Gotta hand it to you, Kakashi.
Your skills of deduction
are impressive!
きた！
Here it comes!
尾が５本　五尾か。
From the number of tails…
It's Five Tails!
木ノ葉壊岩升！
うわっ！
Leaf Rock Crush!
サ…　サンキューだってばよ。
Hey, thanks!
《狙いは　八尾か》
He's after the Eight Tails!
（ビー）すまねえ　八っつぁん
大丈夫か？
Sorry, Eight-o! You okay?
（八尾）痛みは同じだろ。
お前こそ大丈夫か　ビー。
We share pain, remember?
What about you? You okay, Bee?
He tried to attack him?
《コイツ　ヤツを攻撃しようとした？》
（五尾）苦しい。
So painful…!
この私が　こんなヤツに…。
Huh?!
How can I let a bastard
like him do this to me…?
（ビー）この！
Why you…!
おっ　やったか？
There! He did it!
尾獣の力を　なぜ止める？
わからない。
Why would he suppress
the Tailed Beast's powers?
I don't know…
ただ　尾獣は完全には
コントロールできていないようだ。
He doesn't seem to
have the Tailed Beast
completely under his control.
だからかもしれん。
Maybe that's why…
グオォ…。
おい　聞こえたか　ナルト？　声だ。
Hey, did you hear
that voice, Naruto?
聞こえた。
I heard it.
あれは　尾獣。　五尾の声だ。
That was the Tailed Beast…
Five Tails' voice.
グゥ…。
俺たち　尾獣にも
ちゃんと感情がある。
We Tailed Beasts have emotions.
ああいう扱いをされるのを見ると
さすがに腹が立つ。　うっ…。
It pisses me off to see one of
my kind treated like that!
Ouch!
（九尾）ケッ　何を今さら。
Now you get mad?
（九尾）わしたち尾獣を
ペットにしてきた忍たちが→
It's always been the same
with every shinobi
who has kept us as pets!
ずっとやってきたことだ。
Eight Tails…you and that brat Bee
are a special exception.
八尾　テメエとビーとかいうガキだけが
特別なだけだ。
フン　どうだかな　九尾？
I wonder about that Nine Tails…
Huh?
え？　九尾のヤツ
八尾と話できるのか？
Nine Tails can talk to Eight Tails?
I know all about it, Nine Tails.
俺はわかってんぜ　九尾。　お前…。
– You…
– You talk too much!
ゴチャゴチャうるせえ！
By the way, Eight Tails,
仮にもテメエは　尾の数からいっても
わしの次に強い八尾だろ。
given the number of tails
you have,
aren't you the next
most powerful after me?
さっさとやっちまえ。
わしは寝るとこだ。
Hurry up and finish this!
I'm going to take a nap!
Don't decide who's stronger
based on the tail count!
尾の数で強い弱いを
決めんじゃねえよ！
テメエは昔からそうだ。
You've always been like this!
だから　一尾のタヌキに
特に嫌われてんだ。
That's why that Tanuki
One Tail really hates you!
って　聞いてんのか　この野郎！
Are you even listening, you fool?!
キツネがタヌキ寝入り
してんじゃねえぞ。　コラ！
Don't you dare play possum,
you fox!
ハハハッ　八尾と九尾がケンカしてる。
Eight Tails and Nine Tails
are arguing…
Through telepathy
the Tailed Beasts speak…
尾獣同士はテレパシーで会話。
それってレアだし　すっごいわ。
It's not only rare,
but an amazing feat!
ヘヘヘ…。
What're you mumbling about,
Naruto?!
さっきから
なに　ブツブツ言ってんの　ナルト？
来るよ　敵。　俺が来たからって→
The enemy's approaching!
Just because I'm here doesn't
mean you can breathe easy!
気　抜くな！
オス！
Right!
（カカシ）どれがどのペインの術を
使ってくるのか→
We need to confirm which one
is going to use
which one of Pain's jutsu!
まずは確認だ　ガイ。
（ガイ）人の顔を覚えるのが→
Got it, Guy?
I'm not good at
remembering faces…
苦手な俺には
コイツら全部　同じに見えるのだが。
And they all look the same to me…
（カカシ）雷切！
（ガイ）八門遁甲　第六景門開！
Lightning Blade!
Eight Inner Gates!
Sixth Gate of Joy, Open!
（ガイ）３人　そっちへ行ったぞ　ナルト！
Three are headed your way, Naruto!
来たってばよ。
They're here!
Three is better than what
we faced before…
（ビー）３人なら　さっきよりはマシ。
こっちは　さっきよりマジ。
I'm serious now too, hard core!
とぉ！
《チャクラの吸収　口寄せ
引き寄せと飛ばし→
Chakra Absorption…
Summoning…
Magnetic Pull and Repulsion…
チャクラの引き抜き　カラクリ…。
Chakra Extraction…
Puppetry…
どういうことだ？
どれも使ってこない》
What's going on?
They're not using any of those!
ぐっ！
ぐわっ！
どうしてだ？
ペインの術を使ってこないぞ。
Why?!
They're not using any
of Pain's jutsu!
使えないのかもしれないな。
Maybe…they can't.
すでに知られ　対処法の
わかっている　ペインの他の術。
Maybe he's shrewd enough
not to waste any chakra
わざわざチャクラをさいてまで
使えるようにするほど→
on Pain's jutsu since we already
know how to counter them!
バカじゃないってことか。
瞳力だけで　６体もの尾獣を
完全にコントロール下に置くには→
Yeah. In order to control
six Tailed Beasts
with just his Visual Prowess,
相当のチャクラを使うだろうからな。
he must use an enormous amount
of chakra.
さすが　カカシ先生
またまたすごい理解力！
Gotta hand it to you,
Kakashi Sensei!
There's your deductive skill again!
はたけカカシ　よく見抜く
いい眼を持ってるな。
Kakashi Hatake…
He's got very discerning eyes.
さて　では
少し強がってみるとしよう。
Well then…
I'll just power it up a little.
次は２匹だ。
Next up, two beasts.
うわっ！
ぐはっ！
（ガイ）ぐあっ！
クソッ　九尾チャクラ影分身で
陽動しかけて→
Damn it,
I'll have to use Nine Tails'
Chakra Shadow Clones
to create a diversion…
お面野郎を
ハナから狙うしかねえか！
and attack the masked guy head on!
これ以上　九尾チャクラで分身はダメだ。
You can't use any more
Nine Tails' chakra
for Shadow Clones!
お前のチャクラを九尾に取られて
本当に死ぬぞ。
Nine Tails will take
your own chakra…
And you'll drop dead
昇天！　ズレまくりの意気衝天！
Then you'll be seeing red!
ビー　お前　まだ気づかねえのか？
Bee, haven't you noticed yet?
拳を合わせたはずだろうが。
I thought you bumped fists
with him!
そんだけ分身してりゃ
とっくにナルトは瀕死のはずだ。
Given the number of clones
he's already produced,
Naruto should have been
half-dead a while back.
そうなってねえってことは
九尾が　ナルトのチャクラを取ることを→
Seeing as he's not means that
Nine Tails stopped taking
途中でやめてるってことだ。
Naruto's chakra sometime ago.
なあ　九尾。
Right, Nine Tails?
お前らに
何があったか知らねえけどな。
Although I don't know
what happened between you two…
((なあ　九尾　俺はな→
You know, Nine Tails…
いつか　オメエの中の憎しみも→
I'm coming after all that hate
inside you, too, some day!
(どうにかしてやりてぇと
思ってる))
Who the hell are you to decide…
((尾獣と一緒にいることが
不幸せだと→
that having a Tailed Beast
inside me makes me unhappy?!
(勝手に思い込むんじゃねえよ！))
（ガイ）何じゃ　こりゃ！？
What the heck is that?!
Whatever you do,
don't let it touch you, Guy!
（カカシ）なんにしても
触れるなよ　ガイ！
うわっ！
ぐっ！　くっ…。
うっ…　うわっ！
くっ！
おっ！？
くっ～！
ナルト！
Naruto!
助けねば！
ガイ　まずはこっちだ。
We gotta help him!
Guy, we have to deal
with this side first!
こっちだって十分やばいでしょ！
This is bad too!
んっ！？　挟まれた！
We're being surrounded!
うおっ！
木が一気に枯れた！
腐らせるガスか！
The tree wilted instantly!
Is it a corrosive gas?
《チャクラ量が心配だが　しかたない》
I'm worried about
how much chakra I have left,
but I have no choice.
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
ガイ　お互い背中は任せるとして
前に集中する！　文句あるか？
Guy…
We have to guard
each other's back
and focus only on
what's in front of us.
Any complaints?!
ない！
Nope!
雷伝！
Lightning Cable!
第六景門　開！
Sixth Gate of Joy, Open!
朝孔雀！
Asakujaku!
次がきそうだ！
Here comes the next wave!
こっちもだ！
Same here!
さっさと片付けて
ナルトをフォローするぞ！
Let's wrap this up and help Naruto!
く…　くっ！
ナルトを離せ！　このサル！
Let Naruto go, you monkey!
ぐっ…　くっ！
九尾　向こうのマダラと
やりあってた分身ナルトに→
Nine Tails…
I think you gave some
of your chakra
to the Naruto's clone who was
fighting the other Madara.
お前の力を
貸してやったみてぇだな。
（八尾）今回も　その気なら力を
貸してくれても構わねえぞ　コラ。
You should lend this one
strength too before it's too late.
（九尾）わしは　お前とは違う　八尾。
I'm not like you, Eight Tails.
そう何度も何もなく→
I won't wag my tails each and
every time for my Jinchuriki…
人柱力に
尻尾を振ったりはしねえ。
お前　ナルトが
どうなってもいいのかよ！？
Don't you care what happens
to Naruto?!
((マダラ：九尾。
Nine Tails…
今のお前は　一時に結節した
仮の姿に過ぎん。
This transient form is nothing more
than a nodule.
分散した力の一部でしかない。
You're only a piece of yourself.
黙れ。
Shut up.
知の足らぬ
ただの不安定な力でしかない。
You are just an ignorant
unstable power…
黙れ！
Shut up.
Those who shall guide
you are the Uchiha.
お前に導きを与える者
それが　うちはだ。
お前ら尾獣は
瞳力者の　しもべでしかない。
You Tailed Beasts are
simply servants
of those with Visual Prowess!
黙れ！！
Shut the hell up!
（マダラ）従え。
Obey!
（柱間）九尾…
お前の力は強大すぎる。
Nine Tails…
Your power is too great.
(悪いが　野放しにはしておけん))
Regrettably, I cannot
let you run loose.
どんなことを語ろうが…。
No matter what words they use…
((ミト：あなたが力をふるえば
憎しみを引き寄せる。
When you exert your power,
you draw hatred to you.
(私の中で
じっとしていてください))
Please stay quiet inside me.
人間の語ることは…。
Humans all say…
((クシナ：あなたも私も→
This is unfortunate for both of us…
ついてるほうじゃないのは確かね。
(あなたは世界の抑止
そして私は　あなたの抑止))
You may be here to keep
the world in check,
but I'm here to watch you.
…the same thing.
いつも　皆　同じだ。
((九尾：今度は　こんなガキか。
忍どもめ。
And now, it's this brat?
How dare these shinobi…
どのみち　コイツも…。
I'll bet even he…
なあ　九尾。
You know, Nine Tails…
俺はな　いつか
おめぇの中の憎しみも→
I'm coming after all that hate
inside you, too, some day!
(どうにかしてやりてぇと
思ってる))
うっ…　くっ…　くっ…。
あっ…　あっ…。
ナルト！！
Naruto!
うわ～っ！！
なんだ？
What the—?!
Now you want to take my power too?
（四尾）今度は　お前が
俺の力を　ぶん取る気か？
こんなところまで
入ってきやがって。
Coming all the way in here…
you obnoxious brat!
クソガキ　キーッ！！
A-Are you…
こ…　これって…。
Four Tails?!
四尾！？
俺を四尾なんて呼ぶんじゃねえ。
Don't call me "Four Tails"!
ちゃんと名がある。
I have a proper name!
俺は　水簾洞の美猿王！
I am the handsome
Monkey King of Suirendo,
六道仙人より
孫の法号を与えられし仙猿の王！
the King of Sage Monkeys,
bestowed with
the priestly title "Son"
from the Sage of Six Paths!
孫悟空！
斉天大聖だ！　ウキーッ！！
The Great Monkey
Equal of Heaven, Son Goku!
えっ？　え…　あ…
どれが名前？　あ…。
Huh? Uh…
Which one's your name?
孫悟空だ！
It's Son Goku!
フン　やっぱ人間は　バカばかりだな。
名前も　ろくに覚えられねえ。
You humans are all stupid!
You can't even get
a name straight!
猿以下だ。　そんなヤツらに
俺の力は　やりたく…。
You are all lesser than apes.
I don't want to give my power
to likes of such…
てか…　なんだ　ここ！？
九尾のとこと似てんぞ　これ！
So where are we?
It sorta looks like
Nine Tails' place…
聞いてんのか　テメエ！！
Did you hear me, kid?!
俺様の名前を適当に聞いたうえに
無視してんじゃねえぞ！
I told you my name!
Don't you dare ignore me!
失礼すぎんだろ！
You're so rude!
いや…　その…　ごめん。
Huh? Oh…
S-Sorry.
テメエ…
人間のわりには　素直なヤツだな。
You're…pretty genuine for a human.
尾獣に謝るヤツなんてのは
初めてだぜ。
It's the first time I've heard
someone apologize to
a Tailed Beast.
どうやら俺の力を　ぶん取りに
来たわけじゃなさそうだな。
I guess you didn't come to
steal my power, eh?
お前の中にもいるな。
You have one inside you too…
だから　ここへ入れたのか？
That's how you got in…
Kurama's trained
his Jinchuriki well.
九喇嘛は
人柱力のしつけがいいと見える。
九喇嘛…　九喇嘛って？
Kurama?
Who's Kurama?
てめぇ　九尾の本名も知らねえのに
九尾の人柱力やってんのか？
How can you be
the Nine Tails' Jinchuriki
and not even know his real name?!
これだから人間は…。
That's why humans disgust me!
え～っ！？　九尾にも名前あったの？
Huh?! The Nine Tails
has a name too?!
チッ…。
そっか…　九喇嘛ってんだ。
I see, his name's Kurama!
お前ら　人間は　俺たちを
ただの力としか見てねえ。
You humans only see us
as sources of power.
だから　名前すら知らねえし
知ろうともしねえ。
You don't even care
if we have names,
or care to know them.
俺たちを閉じ込め
存在を否定する。
You imprison and deny us
of our existence.
((ほら　例の子よ。
Look, it's that boy.
関わるな。　通り過ぎろ。
Ignore him and keep walking.
あの子　誰？
お前は知らなくていい。
Who's that boy?
You don't need to know.
えい！
キャーッ！
うわっ！　な…　なんだ！？　こりゃ！
アハハハハ！
What the—?!
(あのガキ！
ベーッ！))
That brat!
少しだけど
お前の気持　わかんよ。
I think I understand a little
about how you feel.
I used to misbehave a lot.
俺は　よく　イタズラやった。
叱られたくって…。
I just wanted to be scolded.
はぁ？
Huh?
人の気を引くためなら
なんだって　よかったんだ。
I'd do anything to get people
to notice me.
自分がなくなるよりは
ずっと　ましだったからな。
It was better than being invisible.
俺は　人柱力だ。
I'm a Jinchuriki…
けど　ちゃんと
大切な　ナルトって名前がある。
But I have a proper name
I cherish…
両親と師匠の形見だ。
フン…。
だから…。
((俺は誰でもない。
誰でもいたくないのさ。
(ただ　月の眼計画をなせれば
それでいい))
自分を誰でもいいなんて言う
あんなヤツが…。
((絶望しかない　この世界に
存在する価値はない))
お前らを言いなりにさせてんのが
我慢ならねえ！
なら　お前は
俺たちと　どうしたいってんだ？
ビーのおっちゃんと…。
ビーのおっちゃんと
八尾みてぇになりてぇ。
はぁ？
八尾と冗談言い合ったり
ケンカしたり　励まし合ったり…。
はっきり　口では言えねえけども
近くで見てると　わかる。
まるで　友達みてぇでよ。
んで…　いっつも
俺ってば　こう思うんだ。
むっちゃ　うらやましいってよ。
アハハハハ！
人間のお前が　まさか　本気で→
尾獣と友達になりてぇなんて
言うんじゃねえだろうな？
ギャハハハハハ…！
あぁ？
《コイツ…　本気で言ってやがる》
だから　俺は　お前も助けてぇ。
えっと…　なんだっけ？　名前。
孫でいい。
で…　お前　俺に食われてっけど
どうすんだ？
あっ！　そうだったってばよ。
どう…　どうしよう？
あ…　え…　う～ん。
《面のヤツよりは　ましみたいだな》
俺を止める方法なら　あるぜ。
えっ？
代わりに　鎖を
解いてくれるってんなら→
教えてやらんでもない。
孫！
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
２時間スペシャル。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手→